Thomas Szasz Papers
Thomas Szasz Papers
1890-2011
Szasz, Thomas Stephen, 1920-2012.
196.25 linear ft.
Papers of the Hungarian-American psychiatrist and scholar. Collection contains correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, writings, audio and video recordings.
148694
Biographical History
Thomas Szasz (1920-2012) was an American psychiatrist and scholar, best known for his criticisms of psychiatry and of the influence of modern medicine on society, as well as the intersection of law and psychiatry.
Born in Budapest, Hungary, April 15 1920, Thomas Stephen Szasz emigrated to the United States in 1938. He received his medical education at the University of Cincinnati and his psychiatric training at the University of Chicago Clinics. In 1956 he became Professor of Psychiatry at the State University of New York, Upstate Medical Center in Syracuse, New York, a post he held until 1990 when he became Professor Emeritus. He was a well-known social critic of the moral and scientific foundations of psychiatry, and of the social control aims of medicine in modern society, as well as of scientism. A libertarian, Szasz advocated for the legalization of all drugs, the abolition of involuntary incarceration, and "the right to be mentally ill." Szasz was a prolific author with strong opinions on the relationship between modern psychiatry and the state, and his writings often evoked lively debate and conversations. His books include The Myth of Mental Illness (1960) and The Manufacture of Madness: A Comparative Study of the Inquisition and the Mental Health Movement (1970).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thomas Szasz Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, financial material, memorabilia, subject files, writings by Szasz and by others, and media.
Biographical material contains biographical and autobiographical sketches, both published (e.g., in Who's Who in America) and unpublished.
Correspondence-subject files contains both incoming and (because Szasz regularly retained carbons of his letters) outgoing correspondence. A small amount of family correspondence is filed first, including his parents, brother George, and daughters Margot and Suzy. The vast majority of the correspondence is with readers, editors, publishers, medical colleagues (physicians, psychiatrists, psychologists), lawyers, medical journals, and others with whom he interacted professionally. Individuals and organizations of note include Melvin Belli, Burton Blatt, William F. Buckley, the Church of Scientology (in both the United States and other countries), Timothy Leary, the New York Times, and Karl Popper. Many of the correspondents also appear in the Subject files and in the Writings by others series; the researcher is encouraged to review the full finding aid thoroughly to ensure locating all relevant material.
Financial material consists almost entirely of royalty statements from American and foreign publishers. There are a few folders of bills and financial settlements.
Memorabilia contains awards, personal documentation relating to military service and naturalization as a US citizen, photographs, printed material about Szasz (clippings, reprints, journal articles), scrapbooks, and travel receipts and souvenirs.
Recordings contains audio and video recordings, some commercial but most home-made. Included here are recordings of Szasz speaking at conferences, appearing on radio or television programs, being interviewed, delivering lectures, and so on. Others who appear include Elie Wiesel, Jacqui Rutten, Ralph Slovenko, and more. There are also a few transcribed telephone calls and some commercially-produced and sold items.
As part of his approach to research and writing, Szasz maintained extensive Subject files on people, events, ideas, and topics pertinent to his work. Folder titles in this series are, wherever possible, Szasz's own titles taken either from the folder itself or from his handwritten annotation on items within a folder. Topics range from AIDS, cartoons, and faith healing to John Hinckley Jr., the Tylenol cyanide tampering scare, and witchcraft.
Writings by Szasz are subdivided into articles, books, book chapters, interviews, introductions, letters to the editor, reviews, speeches, and miscellaneous items. In many cases -- with the books in particular -- there are numerous drafts with major or minor edits.
Writings by others includes drafts, typescripts, advance reading copies, and bound (but not published) articles, essays, papers, books, book chapters, and so on. In many cases the authors were requesting Szasz's thoughts or input on their work, or were expressing their gratitude for his influence on their thinking. One unusual item is the three folders of humorous skits written (and presumably performed) by Szasz's interns and residents which parody or make fun of Szasz and other notable psychiatrists. Also in this series are the drafts of Living With It, an autobiography/memoir by Szasz's daughter Suzy.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent; a small amount of family correspondence is filed first. All other series are arranged alphabetically by type of material and/or by title of item. Within Memorabilia, clippings about Szasz and travel receipts are arranged chronologically.
Separated Material
A number of books that were donated as part of the collection have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to and search for "Gift of Thomas Szasz" to locate these items.
Approximately 9 linear feet of material has been removed from the collection due to issues of medical and legal privacy.
Subject and Genre Headings
Religion and philosophy; Science and medicine; Activism and social reform; American Association for the Abolition of Involuntary Mental Hospitalization.; American Civil Liberties Union.; Asclepius at Syracuse.; British Broadcasting Corporation.; Church of Scientology of California.; Citizens Commission on Human Rights International.; Committee on Institutional Psychiatry.; Doubleday & Company, Inc.; Drug Policy Foundation.; Evolution of Psychotherapy conference.; Harper & Row, Publishers.; International Forum on Antiprohibition of Drugs.; John Wiley & Sons.; Libertarian Party.; Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.) -- Press.; Macmillan Company; National Institute of Mental Health (U.S.); Upstate Medical University (N.Y.); Syracuse Psychiatric Hospital; Syracuse University Press.; United States. Public Health Service.; Alexander, George J.; Bazelon, David L. (David Lionel), 1909-1993.; Belli, Melvin M., 1907-1996.; Berrigan, Daniel.; Bettelheim, Bruno.; Blatt, Burton, 1927-1985.; Breggin, Peter Roger, 1936-; Buckley, William F. Jr.; Cobbett, William, 1763-1835.; Frank, Leonard Roy.; Freud, Anna, 1895-1982.; Freud, Sophie, 1924-; Goffman, Erving.; Grenander, M. E. (Mary Elizabeth), 1918-; Halpern, Abraham M. (Abraham Meyer), 1914-1985.; Hayakawa, S. I. (Samuel Ichiyé), 1906-1992.; Horowitz, Irving Louis.; Kazan, Elia.; Kubie, Lawrence S. (Lawrence Schlesinger), 1896-1973.; Leifer, Ron, 1932-; Lipton, Samuel D., 1916-1984.; Loria, Donald W.; Marmor, Judd.; May, Rollo.; Menninger, Karl A. (Karl Augustus), 1893-1990.; Metesky, George P., 1903-1994.; Popper, Karl R. (Karl Raimund), 1902-1994.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972.; Raico, Ralph.; Richman, Sheldon L.; Roazen, Paul; Robitscher, Jonas B.; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813.; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970.; Scott, W. Clifford M.; Slovenko, Ralph.; Strupp, Hans Herrman.; Szasz, Suzy.; Szasz, Thomas Stephen, 1920-2012.; Tanay, Emanuel.; Torrey, E. Fuller (Edwin Fuller), 1937-; Vice, Janet, 1951-; Wain, Louis, 1860-1939.; Wootton, Barbara, 1897-1988.; Journal of Humanistic Psychology.; National review (New York); New England journal of medicine.; New republic (Washington, D.C.); New York times.; Playboy (Chicago, Ill.); The Humanist (Washington, D.C.); The Lancet (London); Addiction.; Antipsychiatry.; Circumcision.; Drug control.; Drug legalization.; Drugs -- Law and legislation.; Homosexuality.; Humanism.; Hungarian Americans.; Involuntary treatment -- Moral and ethical aspects.; Involuntary treatment -- Law and legislation.; Insanity (Law); Insanity defense.; Mental illness.; Law -- Philosophy.; Pain -- Psychological aspects.; Psychiatric ethics.; Psychiatric hospitals.; Psychiatrists -- United States.; Psychiatry -- Congresses.; Psychiatry -- Germany.; Psychiatry -- South Africa.; Psychiatry -- Philosophy.; Psychiatry -- United States.; Psychoanalysis -- Moral and ethical aspects.; Psychoanalysis and homosexuality.; Public policy -- United States.; Radicalism -- History -- 20th century.; Schizophrenia.; Scientology.; Social psychiatry.; Sociological jurisprudence.; Suicide -- Moral and ethical aspects.; War on drugs.; 16mm (photographic film size); Articles.; Audiocassettes.; Awards.; Book reviews.; Briefs (legal documents); CDs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Conference proceedings.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); DVDs.; Essays.; Galley proofs.; Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Negatives (photographs); Passports.; Photographs.; Plaques (flat objects); Postcards.; Posters.; Proofs (printed matter); Reprints.; Research notes.; Royalty statements.; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings.; Speeches (documents); Transcriptions.; VHS.; Video recordings.; Physicians.; Psychiatrists.; Psychotherapists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to recordings requires advance notice to produce a use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas S. Szasz, 1969-2009.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Autobiographical sketches (Box 1)
  - American Men and Women of Science, 1972; undated (Box 1)
  - A Bibliography By and About Thomas Stephen Szasz, M.D. 1945-1975 by Alexander Slade, Apr 1976; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Biographical sketches, 1966; 1968,; 1971,; 1979-1980,; 1990-1992,; undated (Box 1)
  - Contemporary Authors, 2007; undated (Box 1)
  - Current Biography, 1974-1975; undated (Box 1)
  - Fontano biography, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Who's Who in America, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965; 1968,; 1970-1976,; 1989,; undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Family, Szasz's parents, children, other relatives; much of the early material is in Hungarian
    - Peters, Margot (daughter), Steve, and Andrew, 1967; 1974,; 1976,; undated; Szasz's oldest daughter, her husband, and son (Box 2)
    - Szasz, George (brother), 1939; 1954,; 1957-1976; 11 folders (Box 2)
      George has difficult handwriting. Letters are often signed just "G" that can look like a "C." A number of the folders contain correspondence to/from others (usually referencing Thomas) including a plethora of letters from "Ursula" (often typed in German, sometimes individual letters and sometimes typed/written on the back of George's).
    - Szasz, George (brother), 1977-1989 (gaps); 1994-1996,; 2001,; undated; 9 folders (Box 3)
    - Szasz, Julius (father) / "Atya", 1950; 1957,; 1959-1960,; undated (Box 3)
      "Atya" is a Hungarian term for "father" so those letters have been filed here. There is some discussion in other letters between Thomas and George addressed to "Anya" (Hungarian term for "mother") about a dispute regarding who has rights to Atya's papers/writings.
    - Szasz, Lily (mother), 1929-1931; 1938,; 1945,; 1952,; 1962,; 1985 (Box 3)
    - Szasz, Rosine (wife), 1953 (Box 3)
    - Szasz, Suzy (daughter), 1969; 1972,; 1977-1980,; undated; Szasz's younger daughter, married name Palmer (Box 3)
    - Unidentified (Box 3)
  - A. M. Heath & Company, 1971-1978; 1982 (Box 4)
  - Aasved, Harry S., 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Adams, Frank, 1979-1984; undated (Box 4)
  - Adams, Joe K., 1958-1975 (Box 4)
  - Advocacy Now, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - The Advocate, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - The Advocates (WGBH, WGBX TV), 1966-1974 (Box 4)
  - Agassi, Joseph, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Albee, George W., 1982 (Box 4)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1966-1976 (Box 4)
  - Alexander, Franz, 1954-1960 (Box 4)
  - Alexander, George J., 1964-1965; 1969-1982,; 1985-1986,; 1994,; 2001 (Box 4)
  - Alexander, Lee, 1962; 1966 (Box 4)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, 1969; Abraham Blumberg (Box 4)
  - Allen, Janice, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Allentown State Hospital, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Alpha Academic (Box 4)
  - The Alternative, 1971; 1974 (Box 4)
  - AmboBooks, See Uitgeverij Ambo.
  - American Academy of Psychotherapists, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - American Association for the Abolition of Involuntary Mental Hospitalization (AAAIMH), 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1956-1960 (Box 4)
  - American Association for Justice, 1972 (Box 4)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1956 (Box 4)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1965-1966; undated (Box 4)
  - American Bar Association, 1959-1960; 1971 (Box 4)
  - American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology, 1954 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1961-1966; 1969-1971,; 1976-1977,; 1990,; undated; includes list of affiliates (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), Central New York Chapter, 1965; 1969-1972 (Box 4)
    See also Ennis, Bruce J.
  - American Conservative Union, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, 1972; 1976-1980 (Box 4)
  - American Flag Committee, 1961 (Box 5)
  - American Fund for Psychiatry, 1956 (Box 5)
  - American Hungarian Studies Foundation, 1964; 1968,; 1971-1973,; 2003 (Box 5)
  - American Imago, 1966 (Box 5)
  - American Institute for Public Service, 1974; 1977,; 1979 (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Forensic Psychiatry, 1980-1983; 2000,; undated (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Medicine, 1994; 1997 (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry, 1957-1964; 1967-1974; correspondence (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry, 1957-1959; 1968; replies to letters (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Psychoanalysis, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Psychotherapy, 1962-1965; 1969-1971,; 1974 (Box 5)
  - American Medical Association, 1954-1962; 1965-1967,; 1973-1975,; 1978-1979,; 1982 (Box 5)
  - American Orthopsychiatric Association, 1959-1960; 1965-1967,; 1970-1971,; 1977 (Box 5)
  - American Psychiatric Association, 1953-1982; 1991-1993,; 2002-2003,; undated (Box 5)
  - American Psychiatric Association Regional Research Conference, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association, 1953-1962; 1965-1968,; 1971-1978,; 1981,; 1993; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - American Psychological Association (APA), 1959-1966; 1969,; 1976,; 1982-1983,; 1998 (Box 6)
  - American Psychologist, 1981-1988; 1994-2001; publication of American Psychological Association (Box 6)
  - American Psychosomatic Society, 1956-1960; 1964 (Box 6)
  - American Sociological Review, 1960; 1964-1966,; 1970 (Box 6)
  - American Spectator, 1983; 1994 (Box 6)
  - American Telephone and Telegraph (AT&T), 1981 (Box 6)
  - American Trial Lawyers Association, 1966-1967; 1970-1971,; 1980 (Box 6)
  - American University, 1995 (Box 6)
  - American University Law Review, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Amorrortu (publisher), 1974 (Box 6)
  - Anchor Books, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Anders, Gunther, 1962-1964 (Box 6)
  - Anderson, James L., 1966; 1969 (Box 6)
  - Andrews, Benjamin J., Jr., 1977; 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Annals of Internal Medicine, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Ansbacher, Heinz, 1960; 1964,; 1972,; 1979 (Box 6)
  - Anthony, Frank, 1964-1967 (Box 6)
  - Antioch Review, 1961-1964; 1971-1977 (Box 6)
  - Antonucci, Giorgio, 1985 (Box 6)
  - APA malpractice insurance, 1989-1992; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Appleby, Lawrence, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Arens, Richard, 1962-1972 (Box 6)
  - Arietti, Silvano, 1957; 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Aring, Charles D., 1953-1980; 1986-1990 (Box 7)
  - Arismendez, Heather N., 1983 (Box 7)
  - Armando Armando (publisher), 1972 (Box 7)
  - Arneson, Genevieve A., 1971 (Box 7)
  - Aron, Harry, 1965-1983 (Box 7)
  - Association for Clinical and Research Studies, 1976; Norman Ellis (Box 7)
  - Association for Humanistic Psychology, 1973; 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Association for the Preservation of Anti-Psychiatric Artifacts, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Association for the Study of Abortion, 1966; 1970 (Box 7)
  - Atheneum Publishers, 1966; 1975 (Box 7)
  - The Atlantic, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1961; 1967-1969,; 1973,; 1983,; 1990,; 1994; general (Box 7)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1966; reader responses (Box 7)
  - Audio-Forum, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Austen Riggs Center, 1953-1965; 1986 (Box 7)
  - Australia tour, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Ausubel, D.P., 1960; 1978 (Box 7)
  - Authors Guild, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Averbach, Albert, 1960; 1964,; 1967 (Box 7)
  - Ayd, Frank J., 1963 (Box 7)
  - Azima, Hassan, See American Psychiatric Association Regional Research Conference.
  - A miscellaneous (Aa-Al), 2 folders (Box 7)
  - A miscellaneous (Ap-Az) (Box 8)
  - Baily, Percival, 1959-1965 (Box 8)
  - Baker, Joseph P., 1994-1996 (Box 8)
  - Ballad, Richard, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Ballinger Publishing Company, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Baltimore Mental Health Association, undated (Box 8)
  - Bandler, Bernard, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Bane, Bernard, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Barchilon, Jose, 1954; 1957,; 1961-1965,; 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Bare Bones Films, 1992-1993; 1996 (Box 8)
  - Barker-Benfield, G.J., 1976-1981 (Box 8)
  - Barney, Ken, 1964-1966; 1969,; undated (Box 8)
  - Bartholomew, Fletcher, 1964-1968; 1981-1983,; 1988 (Box 8)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Basaglia, Franco, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Basic Books, Inc., 1954-1979; 1984,; 1987-1988; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Basil Blackwell (publisher), 1957; 1960,; 1981,; 1984 (Box 8)
  - Basmajian, Carol, 1965-1966; undated (Box 8)
  - Bath, David and Jo, 1970-1973; 1980 (Box 9)
  - Bauer, Peter T., 1965; 1968-1972,; 1975-1977,; 1984,; 1993-1995 (Box 9)
  - Bazelon, David L., 1957-1966 (Box 9)
  - BBC, See British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC).
  - Bean, Philip, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - Beaver, James E., 1967-1971 (Box 9)
  - Becker, Ernest, 1960; 1963-1965,; 1970,; undated (Box 9)
  - Becker, Richard S., 1993 (Box 9)
  - Begelman, D. A., 1964-1966; 1970,; 1976 (Box 9)
    See also Tolor, Alexander.
  - Behavior Today, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Behavioral Science, 1957-1958 (Box 9)
  - Behavioral Science Book Service, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Behavioral Sciences Tape Library, 1969-1971 (Box 9)
  - Bellak, Leopold, 1957-1962; 1966 (Box 9)
  - Belli, Melvin M., 1962-1963 (Box 9)
  - Beluffi, Max, 1964-1981; 1985,; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Benedek, Therese, 1954-1960 (Box 9)
  - Bennett, Linda, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Bensen, Kim, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Berg, Harvey M., 1963-1965 (Box 9)
  - Berg, Helen and Paule, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
  - Berg, Ralph, 1967; 1979 (Box 9)
  - Berke, Joseph H., 1972 (Box 9)
  - Berman, Alfred, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
  - Berman, Leo, undated (Box 9)
  - Bernardo, Antonio Carlos, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Berne, Eric, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Bernstein, David, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Berrigan, Daniel, 1969; 1972-1973,; undated (Box 9)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
  - Bharati, Agehananda, 1960-1961; 1975,; 1977 (Box 9)
  - Bibace, Roger, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - Binet, Francis E., 1962 (Box 9)
  - Birnbaum, Manaker & Aquilio, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Bisharet, Mary, 1973; 1980 (Box 10)
  - Blatt, Burton, 1969-1972; 1975-1981,; 1984,; undated (Box 10)
  - Bleck, Eugene E., 1970 (Box 10)
  - Bleuler, Manfred, 1957; 1959 (Box 10)
  - Block, Walter, 1980-1981; 1988 (Box 10)
  - Bloom, Victor, 1965; 1992 (Box 10)
  - Blumberg, Abraham S., 1970-1971; 1978 (Box 10)
    See also Alfred A. Knopf.
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield, 1954-1958; 1974,; 1990 (Box 10)
  - Boatner, Yandell, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
  - Bobgan, Martin M., 1979; 1986 (Box 10)
  - Bocskor, Catherine E., See Hungarian government, claims against.
  - Bodin, Arthur, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Böhm, Tomas, 1969-1973; undated (Box 10)
  - Bolt, Richard A., 1981-1984; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Bonnier Forlag (publisher), 1973 (Box 10)
  - Books for Libertarians, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Borelli, Nelson, 1963-1965; 1978-1980 (Box 10)
  - Borowich, Abba E., 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Bossio, Giuseppe Bruno, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Boston Psychoanalytic Society and Institute, 1959-1962 (Box 10)
  - Boyer, Ernest L., 1973 (Box 10)
  - Bradford, R. W., 1990; 1994-1997 (Box 10)
  - Brampton, George F., 1965; 1969 (Box 10)
  - Bramson, Leon, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Braun, Samuel, 1959; 1962,; 1965 (Box 10)
  - Breggin, Peter, 1964-1966; 1970-1981,; undated; includes numerous papers, articles, etc. by him; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Brenner, Benjamin, 1963; 1966 (Box 11)
  - Brillmayer, Robert, 1970 (Box 11)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1964; 1971-1975,; 1978-1986,; 1996; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1972; coverage and viewer responses to Szasz's appearance on the show "Controversy" (Box 11)
  - British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, 1956-1958; 1976-1977 (Box 11)
  - British Journal of Medical Psychology, 1957-1959; 1962,; 1976,; 1992-1993,; 1996 (Box 11)
  - British Journal of Psychiatry, 1976; 1980,; 1985,; 1988,; 1992,; 1995-1997,; 1999 (Box 11)
  - British Journal of Psychotherapy, 1994; 1998 (Box 11)
  - British Journal of Sexual Medicine, 1981 (Box 11)
  - British Medical Journal (BMJ), 1961; 1965,; 2001 (Box 11)
  - Brooks, Alexander D., 1960; 1966,; 1969-1970,; 1978,; 1983 (Box 11)
  - Brosin, Henry W., 1958-1959 (Box 11)
  - Brown, Carlton, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Brown, Douglas P., 1971; 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - Brown, Mortimer, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Bry, Ilse, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
  - Buchholtz, Samuel S., 1960-1961; 1965 (Box 11)
  - Buckley, William F. Jr., 1963; 1973-1977,; 1981,; 1988-1989,; 1996,; undated; founder and editor-in-chief of National Review (Box 11)
    See also National Review.
  - Buda, Bela, 1965-1966; 1973-1976,; 1980-1982,; 1987,; 1990 (Box 11)
  - Buffalo Evening News, 1970; 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Bugental, James F.T., 1965-1967; 1996,; 1999; includes "Handbook of humanistic psychology" (Box 11)
  - Burger, Warren E., 1961; 1964 (Box 11)
  - Burghard, Shirley, 1962-1965; 1975,; undated (Box 11)
  - Burke, Edward, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Burke, Monique, 1978; 1990,; 1993-1994,; undated (Box 12)
  - Burrelle's Press Clipping Service (Box 12)
  - Burston, Daniel, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Burton, Arthur, 1957-1963; 1966 (Box 12)
  - Byrne, Paul V., 1964-1967; undated (Box 12)
  - B, miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Cahn, Edmond, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Cain, Leonard D., 1972 (Box 12)
  - Calder and Boyars Ltd., 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Caldwell, Julius, 1966 (Box 12)
  - California Board of Medical Quality Assurance, 1984 (Box 12)
  - California State University, Fullerton, 1974-1976 (Box 13)
  - California State University, Sacramento, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Calvin College, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Cambridge House, 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1962; 1986,; 2000 (Box 13)
  - Campaign Against Psychiatric Atrocities, 1969-1971 (Box 13)
  - Canadian Medical Association Journal, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Canadian Mental Health Association, 1974 (Box 13)
  - Capell, Martin D., 1965-1970; 1974-1986; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Caputo, John D., 1987 (Box 13)
  - Carino, Ronald, 1975-1979; undated (Box 13)
  - Carrera, Jose, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Carter, Catherine H., 1967; 1971,; 1976-1977 (Box 13)
  - Casa Editrice il Saggiatore, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Casella, Louis J., 1966 (Box 13)
  - CATO Institute, 1977; 1979,; 1981-1983,; 1988-1992,; 2003,; undated (Box 13)
  - Cavallo Foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
  - Cavett, Dick (Dick Cavett Show), 1970-1972 (Box 13)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1955; 1972,; 1980,; 1982,; undated (Box 13)